Next, you want to talk about is transparent components.
And so this is where this is going to become actually rather critical.
You want to take a look at our code base.
And one of the things you'll notice here is that if you take a look at say,
like the input field, this is another common one where
let's face it forms or about like 95% of our bread and butter
as web developers.
And so it would make sense for us to basically take this form control that we have here,
where we have a typical task input of text,
and then basically wrap it in a component that can then be reused.
Because then our styles and stuff can propagate,
and we don't have to deal with all this all the time.
So your first instinct when you're thinking of this is like,
all right, cool, we're going to go ahead,
let's create a base text input.
That's what we're going to do.
All right.
So we'll take this bit here, this whole title,
and we're going to go ahead and so I'm going to go ahead and queue up
the single file components, did not install SAS,
so that won't be applicable.
And we'll drop it in here.
OK, first thing first.
So let's go ahead and don't let's ignore this.
Let's not worry about the V model for now.
This is good.
We've got a placeholder.
We have disabled, OK, setting, and whether it's required or not.
OK, so typically when we're designing components,
your first instinct might be to define props for everything on one of these.
But this is, that would be a lot, right?
Because then your base is just kind of recreating the DOM API.
And so what we really need is to think about what we want to do as far as,
like, OK, we want to configure specific things
that we're going to use within this base text input.
So let's start with some of the obvious ones.
So the first one is we're going to want to always give it a label.
So that'll be typed, string, oh, wait.
Yeah, did that, required, true.
And so we know that here, for example, we can say, OK, the label will go here.
And then here, we have this thing where we also need to pair the four
attribute with the ID.
So usually I find this actually just easier to just call it ID.
And then this way, we'll just use the populate both.
So then type string required, true.
And then we can just populate here.
And here.
OK, so that's good.
Whether it's disabled or not, that is something that you would think
that you want to define.
But honestly, this is actually something we would want to be able to just
pass through, because this is part of the native input.
And so not something you necessarily want to configure.
And whether it's required or not, that you also think, yeah, that should
be something that should just be passed through as well.
And so then you're also probably thinking, OK, well, then, yeah,
actually, in fact, what I really want is for most of the attributes
that view passes to go to this input element.
Because really, this is the whole purpose of us creating this reusable piece.
The label is really not what's being customized.
Ninetyth is this form control that we're wrapping around.
And so the question is, how do we do that?
And so using what we just learned about, what we could do,
you're probably thinking, is, well, couldn't we do this v-bine equals?
And then, if you didn't know this, we have this thing called dollar sign
adders, which is stands for attributes.
And so what view does essentially is take all the attributes that you
pass this custom component and then sends it to whatever element
that you want it to, like, basically, you're assigning it to.
So when you do this, let's go ahead and actually bring this up.
So what I'm going to do, I'm going to do this.
OK, we're going to go ahead and we're going to create a quick view
real quick. I'm going to call this sandbox.samboxpage.view.
And this page is just going to serve as something separate from the application code.
And that way, we can just basically queue it up and see different demos
without interrupting the rest of it.
So I'm going to go ahead and update that real quick.
I would drop this all the way here on the bottom.
So this will be sandbox.
And then, let's read the sandbox page.
OK, we see the arcs of the right.
So if we open this up, OK, yep, it's empty right now.
So that makes sense.
Let me go ahead and fire that up.
Sandboxpage.
There we go.
All right, we see our sandboxpage.
All right, so what I'm going to want to do now is let's go ahead and import
that base text input that we just created.
So base text input is created.
And then we're going to go ahead and bring it on.
And we're going to do, we're going to add a placeholder.
And we're going to call it my test placeholder.
And then, oh, yes, partial holder is not signable.
That's fine.
OK, so we save that.
And then you'll see, here we go.
Here's my text being bound.
And what you notice here is that this placeholder is being
passed correctly, according to the input in this particular case.
But something that should be kept in mind though is that,
especially when you have different routes.
So it's kind of funny that it's working in this particular case.
But what I wanted to demo is the fact that you do sometimes find that
especially with the single route notes, what view typically does,
again, it's kind of interesting that the behavior is happening here,
is that it'll actually send your attributes to the route note.
Because that's what view knows, right?
Whereas if you have, if you think about it another way,
if we had multiple notes here, view has a hard time determining where
to send something to.
And so typically what we want to do is when we're binding the adders,
is you have to do something called basically to disable the inherent attributes.
And so there's this macro inside of the script setup for view,
that's called define options.
And so for those who come from the view two days,
you might recognize it as basically that it would look like this instead.
And you would say, inherent adders false.
So we basically created a macro to make this easier to do,
so that you didn't have to have a script block and a script setup block.
And so this whole thing can then be put inside of here,
and just like that.
And so typically what you'll see in these sort of transparent components,
where you want to make sure where the attributes are being applied to.
And so the reason why we have props here is because if you don't have these props
already defined, view is just going to send everything
along like in the bundle of attributes.
But since you have these props defined for ID and label,
that's what allows you to designate it to other parts of the component besides just the input.
So the thing with this though is that while we have basically we have this here,
if we go ahead and let's go back to our sandbox page,
and let's go and create a ref from view,
and this time we're going to call it const first name equals ref empty,
and we're going to v model this to first name.
Okay, and then let's wrap this main and then we'll go ahead and render out whatever is,
where we think first name should be.
You'll notice that nothing's happening.
And so it's probably like, oh, that's weird.
That's not what I expected because, right?
Like I, we put v model on text inputs all the time, right?
I mean, it's right here.
We did v model to the thing, and then it just talks to the thing.
And so the reason for that is because when you're working with transparent components
and you want to do something like a v model,
you actually have to be very explicit about what it is you're trying to do,
similar to what we were talking about earlier.
So for the base int text input perspective,
what the way you would typically do this, and I want to demonstrate this the long way
first to understand what's happening here, is that you basically define what it is
that you want to bind it to, because what v model ultimately is, when we take a look at it,
so let me go back, let me close this and then go the sandbox page.
What you really trying to say here is that you want the value that's bound to the text input
to be first name, and what you also want to do is when it's on input,
you want it to go ahead and then basically say like first name equals event.target.value.
That's like the long form of what you're trying to do. And so typically the way you
have to accomplish this is that the common here, you know, say, okay, well what we're going to do
that is when it's say, okay, so there's going to be a, let's see, we're going to have a first,
in this case, so it's called model value. This is the prop that's actually bound to be
model by default. And so then we can say type string, and then we'll say default like this,
and then you would also then have to define the emits to then say, okay, we're going to update
then what we updating, we're updating model value. And then from here, you could then say v model
equals model value, just like that. And so all that, if we did this correctly, but
due to v model model cannot be used on a prop prop local binding, you don't have the v model
on your, you're using your component? Oh, you're saying this one,
this should be the v model, right? Yeah, you're right. It's because the ID's required,
that's enough. I think you might be right. Yes, you tracked. That's one of them, and then what
does to be required? We acquired ID and then we have a label. We don't have a label.
Oh, yes, this is when the literature is doing it's job. First name. Okay, fantastic.
Great. Okay, so that's rendering correctly now. And so the v model to the first name,
this one is where it's currently not responding the way I would expect it to.
And even though we have this already bound, which is so fascinating. Okay, I don't want to
do this. Is there have to be something to listen to the admit? So that's what's supposed to be,
okay, so typically what this is what is supposed to be because you're supposed to essentially
be saying Prof. Model value. And here is where we would say on input, we would say admit,
and then we would say update model value, and then event that target that value is what it should be
saying. And then so I need to, where's the admit here? Confidence, sign it, and then like that.
And then it's still, oh, possibly no. That's fine. You can yell at me all you want. Okay, so I'm not sure,
there you go. Now we have it working. Thanks for calling it out. That's right. We have to do it
the long way first because, so you can see this is prone to lots of errors if that doesn't
show anything else. And so over time the team basically realized that this is something we do a lot.
And so instead, this is too much boilerplate. What we can do is instead, we have this new
helper function called use model. And so what use model does is all this boilerplate we just
basically worked through. So in that case, we would say in this case, text value equal, yep,
equals use model or define model is something to say. And then you can, if you want you can pass it
what exactly it'll be. So in this case, we know it's going to be a string. And then this is where
we're going to go ahead and then say I yes. Okay, now that we have this, we don't need all this boilerplate
and we do V model on the text value like this. And then it's the works.
Oops, also I can delete that. And I can delete this.
And so boom, we have this. And so what's nice about this particular V model approach though is that
you can actually then start to expand upon it. Whereas before we have model value, you can actually
start passing arguments as well to your V model. And so the way that would look is that we basically
have the ability to then say, okay, well, inside of my base text input. Let's say we had two text
inputs that we want the first name and last name. So in this particular case, we're going to ignore
this for now. It's for the V binators. You can actually then pass it an argument to basically
then say whether it's the first name or not. So the way that would work is you would say
define model and you would say this is my first name. So let's see, let's make this clearer. So
that's easier to tell. Consulate name, define model string. And this is the last name.
And then what we can do here is, do, do, do. Great. We can go ahead and then say first name here
and then we're going to mine it to here. And then inside of our sandbox view, then we can actually
now say first name is bound to this particular V model inside of the form. And then V model to
and then in this case last name, you can actually find directly to it this way,
like that. And then voila, you should have Smith, Randy. And there you go. So the defined model just
makes it way easier, especially with this. I mean, you could do it before, but it's just a lot more
convoluted. And so the syntax makes it very clean as far as making it, you can start composing
your forms together in some pretty interesting ways. Because you combine the V model to different
form inputs, you can be very creative as far as how that goes.